BILL DIEGO, NGONGANG SOMEN

1993/07/24

<u>Email:</u> bill-diego.ngongang-somen.1@etsmtl.net <u>Linkedin:</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/somendiego

I'm bilingual, I learn fast, I have experience on backend development (Symfony, SQL, Heroku, ...) and Project Management. I'm very professional and I improve myself every day. I've been granted to *Défi Montréal (CRIM)'s* incubator to empower my personal project Edutools and to build the Vortex (an ERP for startupers).

EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2018 – PRESENT

LEAD DEVELOPER, 9308-5785 QUEBEC INC. – MARIA, QC

My main goal is to build an online radio station for "9308-5785 QUEBEC INC". At a glance, people subscribe to the website to get access to the marketplace of music medias, and to subscribe to live channels. Animator via their dashboard broadcast what's going on in the studio or just push music live. — The project is still in design process, will be available online soon.

JULY 2018 - PRESENT

LEAD DEVELOPER, DEFI MONTREAL (CRIM) – MONTREAL, QC

At "Defi-Montreal" I'm working on a startup management: Entrepreneurs can create their profiles, manage their startups, hire people, and make their media marketing; in other hand, Defi Montréal" (the incubator) can manage their activities, teams, projects, events and entrepreneurs. — Vortex (vortex.defimtl.com — beta)

AUG 2018 - PRESENT

CO - FOUNDER / WEB DEVELOPER, GGEM TUTORING - MONTREAL, QC

GGEM Tutoring is a web platform for the company of the same name. My work here was to create all the web application and host it on Heroku. People use GGEM Tutoring to hire tutors for their children. – GGEM Tutoring (www.ggem.academy)

MAY 2018 - PRESENT

CO – FOUNDER / WEB DEVELOPER, MBOADJOSS.COM – YAOUNDE, CM

Mboadjoss is a social network for foreigners of Cameroon. It's built with **WebRTC**, **MongoDB**, **Symfony** and host on **Heroku**. We're working on the mobile application right now! – Mboadjoss (**www.mboadjoss.com**)

FEB 2018 - PRESENT

CO – FOUNDER / WEB DEVELOPER, KAMIX.IO – PARIS, FR

"We are on a mission to develop a remittance service that optimizes the yearly flow of \$ 65 billion sent by African diaspora to their 120 million family members." – Kamix.io (www.kamix.io) I built the web platform of Kamix using Symfony and MongDB.

DEC 2017 - PRESENT

CO - FOUNDER / WEB DEVELOPER, EDUTOOL.CA - YAOUNDE, CM

Edutools is the tools for Education. I designed and built it with Symfony3 and MongoDB. It's a social network for education. We have tools like: Marketplace, Tutoring, School Management, Messaging. – Edutools (www.edutool.ca – beta)

NOV 2017 - PRESENT

CO - FOUNDER - REGIONAL MANAGER, AFRORELIC.COM - PARIS, FRANCE

At AfroRelic we produce digital content for/about Africa with drone! – AfroRelic (www.afrorelic.com)

JUN 2017 - PRESENT

FOUNDER - MANAGER, INNOVAFACTROY.XYZ - YAOUNDE, CM

I built the main site of my company (Cameroon) to showcase our services and products. At innovaFactory we help people get connected to Optical Fiber Networks. – innovaFactory (www.innovafactory.xyz)

FEB 2017 - PRESENT

WEB DEVELOPER, GEN3.XYZ – PARIS, FR

Built for a client in France. It's a genealogic tree web application. People can build their family tree online, share it and connect them to others. – Gen3 (www.gen3.xyz)

JUN 2016 - MAR 2017

DESIGN ENGINEER, HUAWEI TECHNOLOGIES – YAOUNDE, CM

I Worked on maintenance of Optical Network in Yaounde, I managed a team of 15 members and closed issues of 125km of optical fiber network (45 km Yaounde, 80km in Douala). I also performed on-sites surveys and wrote technical narratives.

FEB 2015 - JUN 2015

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - INTERN, COMETAL – DOUALA, CM

I designed a tracking software with modules for inventory monitoring, customer relationship management, staff administration and reports generation. I also collaborated with company employers to create applications based on client's requirements.

JUL 2014 – AUG 2014

PROJECT ENGINEER - INTERN, COMETAL – DOUALA, CM

I co-managed the installation of a food industry at Bekoko (Douala) for OLAM GROUP. The main tasks: Discuss with client about his requirements, Plan project resource exploitation and develop internal processes and plans for project tracking.

FEB 2008 - PRESENT

BACKEND DEVELOPER / TUTOR, OTHER PROJECTS

I worked as a Freelance, I created an e-commerce, cloud printing application, content management software and farm management application.

EDUCATION

SEPT 2019

MASTER OF ENGINEERING - IT, ECOLE DE TECHNOLOGIE SUPERIEURE – MONTREAL, CA

IT Project Management, Service Management, Internet Security, ERP.

FEB 2016

MASTER OF ENGINEERING - MEC, ECOLE NATIONALE SUPERIEURE POLYTECHNIQUE – YAOUNDE, CM

JUL 2010

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA, COLLEGE DES LAUREATS – DOUALA, CM

JUN 2009

GED, LYCEE CLASSIQUE DE BAFOUSSAM - BAFOUSSAM, CM

SKILLS

- ITIL certification (ongoing)
- PMBOK (ongoing)
- Web Programmer (10y)
- Client Management (2y)
- Internet Security (ongoing)
- Languages: French (Senior), English (Good)
- MySQL (5y)

- Symfony (4y) / PHP (7y)
- Bludfire (2m)
- NodeJS / Meteor (2y)
- NoSQL (MongoDB) (4y)
- Salesforce (ongoing)
- AngularJS(2y)
- HTML/CSS (10y) Bootstrap (4y)

ACTIVITIES

Business opportunities analysis, customers management, travel, music, investment opportunities, reading, Software development.